Arturo J. Ossorio Arana

Ecohydrologist - Data Scientist

arturoa91@gmail.com | +54 9 113 636 8323 | linkedin.com/in/ajossorioarana | github.com/ajossorioarana | ajossorioarana.github.io

ABOUT ME

Ecohydrologist geared towards data science, with an analytical background and experience working with stakeholders and managing teams. Currently increasing mastery in Machine Learning. I will be uploading related content through my GitHub account and website.

EXPERIENCE

EcoAqua - Chief of Technical Department

Feb. 2020 - Present | Buenos Aires, Argentina

- + Diagnosed and treated customer's lakes for algae, weeds and water quality issues.
- + Implemented new budgeting process, based on limnological factors, incresing revenue by > 30%.
- + Worked together with COO, improving KPI performance, mainly client retention rate.

EcoAqua - Aquatic Specialitst

Jun. 2017 - Jan. 2020 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

- + Managed five 2-people teams to ensure all services are completed on schedule.
- + Serviced customer's lakes to provide superior quality and service in the fulfillment of all customer needs.
- + Deployed maintainance routine for vehicles and machinery, decreasing workflow interruptions by 40%.

UBA - Graduate Teaching Assistant (Course "Applied Hydraulics")

Aug. 2017 - Present | Buenos Aires, Argentina

- + Been asigned to > 100 students, answering queries and grading assignments.
- + Aided professors in examinations and dictated several practical lectures.
- + Syllabus: Pressurized pipe flow, pump selection, water hammer, open channel flow and weir design.

Buenos Aires City Government - Bid/Tender Assistant

Jun. 2016 - May. 2017 | Buenos Aires, Argentina

- + Cash-flow and finance audit of IBRD-loan WASH project (Arroyo Vega Drainage Tunnel > \$145M).
- + Elaboration of bidding documentation in accordance to IBRD norms and recommendations.

EDUCATION

M.SC. in Ecohydrology

UNLP - ABT, Expected Graduation Date: 2022

Engineer's degree, Civil Engineer

UBA - Graduated 2018

PROJECTS/PUBLICATIONS

EDA on Argentine lakes and reservoirs dataset

- + Python / Seaborn / EDA / CSV / DataViz
- + Polished, visualized and interpreted resultes of Argentine lakes dataset.
- + Obtained Carlson's trophic state index (TSI) for waterboides and presented relevant analysis.

Watershed delineation of Chimehuín river, Patagonia, Argentina

- + QGIS / GRASS
- + Developed map of Chimehuín river basin using processed DEM, with lakes and watercourses marked on it.
- + Created as part of dissertation about exotic willow (Salix fragilis) invasion of patagonian rivers.

>>>This resume was generated entirely in Python. For full sourcecode, view my portfolio.